hello my name is irina welcome back to
another episode of hermitcraft if you
look above me
you'll see that false's score
is only six seconds slower than mine now
that's not a lot the other scores don't
come particularly close two minutes 44
but 138 is dangerously close so i think
i'm at the end of the video because this
electric course does take two minutes
every time i'm gonna try and beat my
score but what you can see is that we
have made
47 diamonds which means if i put that in
my chest we now have over four stacks of
diamonds we may not be the richest
hermit but it's been a while since i've
had this many diamonds in my ender chest
anyway as promised we are going to go
over
to
hermitville because last episode i
promised something rather big
i did promise to bring out the big guns
and i bigged up what the big guns were
hold on hold on a second
every time i come back here
there's some new crazy what the heck
this is why i love the build off so much
there is so many new thing is that ren's
van
and it's taller
and there's a rock
i hold hold on there's too many things
for me to process okay right so let's
start off with the ren's hippie van
hippie van has now taken off and it's fl
that it looks amazing that looks
absolutely fantastic
so ren's van has taken off with some
wings
and is now flying through the air in one
foul swoop he has taken the lead
doesn't look like this build has changed
much but iskal has
somehow defying all laws of this build
build-off not that this build-off has
any laws
yeah having said that there are no laws
look at this weird plant thing he's
brought down
the moon i assume that is with a magnet
someone needs to tell iskal that i don't
know if the moon's magnetic like this
although it might be full of iron
let's let's not question the science of
this
but he's built now a space station on
top of the moon
and
oh no
not only that
he's fired the rocket
right into my house
right in there
straight in the middle of it
impaled
impale this doesn't even achieve
anything
this doesn't help his house get higher
he just he just did this for fun
he just did he just did this because he
could
we definitely saw this coming so it's
not a major surprise it's pretty funny
it's pretty funny so if we just just
digest this scene for a second
do you remember a couple of weeks ago
when this was just three houses trying
to build a tall building now look at it
this is a full-on
build war or something oh man but i've
got to tell you guys i said last episode
i was going to bring out the big guns
and i'll reveal what i was going to do
what i was going to do and i use was in
the past tense because that's not what
i'm going to do anymore
so what i was going to do was go full
transformer mode on this house i was
going to give it shoulders made out of
houses arms made out of houses and a big
old face made out of houses
and i tried to do that in my testing
world and it didn't it didn't look so
good guys it
i've decided not to do that
i've decided not to do that at all
instead
i'm going to take a slightly different
approach but seeing as i've been
attacked both by iskal
and by scar and i'm not sure what's
going on with with the renbob thing but
i definitely can't touch that for the
moment because that is
that is amazing we don't even know what
this is gonna do
i think we might need to wait for this
one to play out
but as you can see we've got a lot of
building to do
and i think it's best
if we just get started strap yourselves
in because we've got a couple of minutes
of time lapse this represents about six
hours of building and you're gonna see
why because it's quite a complex thing
now i've managed to keep it under wraps
exactly what i'm going to be building
but i'm going to let the time lapse
speak for me for the most part so what i
did do was make the house taller
obviously whatever it is i'm making on
top of the build it needs to be the
tallest thing when we're done so i had
to make it just that little bit taller
maybe you can see what i'm making or
maybe it's not clear yet but maybe it
will become a bit more obvious as things
like a tail appear a couple of legs some
claws the big redness of it all
hopefully you guys can work it out if
not it's about to become very clear as i
finish the face that's right i have
decided to build a dragon on top of my
house in the build-off and this is
probably the most challenging thing i've
had to make in a while building organic
structures is incredibly difficult
thankfully i've got a good friend in
pearlescent moon who is very experienced
with dragons so using some of her
techniques that i learned from her and
using a reference picture i was able to
recreate my own dragon on top of this
house if you want to learn how to make
dragons i can't recommend her channel
enough she's extremely talented at
making dragons even i managed to make
one following some of her tips and
tricks either way you can see that this
is starting to take some real shape and
the
really tricky part was the wings getting
the angles on something like this
correct is so much harder than building
a very tall house because you need to
have the wings come forward you need to
have the body work its way around the
house it's just such a complicated thing
to try and build but i wanted to kind of
show that i can do more than just make
really tall houses and hopefully this
did that from down here
this looks absolutely amazing i'm
actually really proud of this build so
the first thing that you might notice is
that it's not actually breathing any
fire now this is intentional
mainly because
i'm not actually that good with the
whole multi-colored glass thing so i'd
have to learn that new technique and i
don't have time for that today however
this is my new defense system no one
should mess with me with a giant dragon
on top of my house everybody knows that
wizards cannot harm a dragon by itself
they need multiple wizards to cast
spells on things like this
and i think what's gonna happen here is
that ren's
rv is gonna run right in the line of
fire and if it does
it's gonna end up with a bit of a
blackened front from all the charring
that's gonna happen
but most importantly this has put me
back on top the highest point is over
there at 135 which is above all of these
contestants
so
your move guys
your move but there's something else
that needs to oh it just looks so
awesome but there's something else that
needs to be addressed
before i can call my move complete and
that is that
you remember the rocket went straight
into the side of my building that's just
not going to fly iskow that like might
the top of the building was here
and so plowing this into my house
accomplishes nothing so what i'm going
to do
is i'm going gonna fire back in
i think what is a really good way so
what i'm gonna do is around here meaning
perhaps there
what we're going to do
and
this will all make sense in a minute but
i've got some tnt here that's right i am
i'm i'm gonna do it
you think i'm not gonna do it i'm i'm
gonna do it
yep i've done it there we go
i've blown a hole
in the side of the aquarium this isn't
actually just an attack with tnt that's
too simple but i did actually need a
hole in that building the reason being
that i'm actually going to build well
let's just let's just go and do it a
giant boxing glove
i just need to make sure i've got the
thumb in there so you can tell what it
is
and the reason i've worked backwards i
started with the tnt
to make sure that i could actually get
the placement right so that is perfect
so he sent a rocket into my house yeah
i've just punched a hole in his aquarium
there we go we have ourselves a boxing
glove and now we just need to attach it
to the side of the building building
that boxing glove was a lot easier than
building a gigantic fire breathing
dragon that's for sure
i've also found a really strange bug if
you spam enough of the scaffolding
blocks quickly enough look i can extend
i can extend it even where it shouldn't
be and then they're like fake
scaffolding blocks like they don't drop
anything but i can still stand on them
this is so strange i wonder if i re-log
what happens oh no no they're
they're gone they're gone
so they're fake invisible blocks that is
so awesome
i can think of so many things that that
could be used for so what we're gonna do
is just create like a zigzag pattern
made out of iron blocks which is very
expensive
rather awkwardly it looks like it's just
about to miss the house so that's why we
work backwards so i'm gonna have to make
this at a bit of an angle which makes
this whole thing a little bit more
tricky but we'll manage oh that looks so
good that looks so good it's got the
angle just right it really looks like
it's a boxing glove that's been
punctured straight into here do you know
what else i should do i think over time
what i should do is use some sponge to
drain this slowly up until this point
i'll leave it an episode but i think it
should slowly drain a little bit
i'm not even sure why this is an
aquarium to be honest
i thought he just encased it in glass
unless the wizard did it if you just
look at everything that's gone on in the
last few episodes
this is absolutely insane but i'm afraid
i have some really bad news everybody
really bad news so while i was building
all of this i went inside my house down
here
and
villager green
is nowhere to be found
nowhere to be found whatsoever i look
down here he can't go down here but i've
looked he's not down there
he's absolutely nowhere to be found
which leads me to think
he's been caught by a zombie and there's
no way in this is really confusing the
only thing i can think of is that i left
the door open which i don't normally do
and a baby zombies just walked in
and taken care of him
but that's that's really sad so
i think what we're gonna have to do
is is just hold a little funeral for him
there's only one other grave in here and
that was from mini stress so stress
you're not the only one who's
permanently lost their villager so
i'll make my gravestone next to yours
digging a grave i don't have i don't
have anything to bury
stress stress is put in an armor stand
but i'm no good at that so we're just
gonna put a couple of red blocks here
and pretend
here lies villager green may he rest in
peace
may he rest in peace indeed it's a fat
it's a very sad day so i think i should
say a few words for him he was a good
villager he didn't really do much he
kind of just stayed in the house and
slept in my bed you know what he really
he really didn't do a lot for me am i
really that i'm i'm not really that
upset he's he he hasn't actually been
very useful
at all but he was a good villager and we
shall miss him
rest in peace village agreeing anyway
let's move on shall we now that we've
got the build-off part done
i heard through the comments that
everyone was spamming at me that
something is going on in the shopping
district a couple new shops have opened
up i'm still so happy with that anyway
let's head over to the old lands
because i've spent far too many hours
building here now i was told that
there's a new there it is storage wars
which sounds an awful lot like a tv show
so let's go and check this out
instruction book
all right give me a second to read this
all right so i've read up just to save
you from reading that as well what i
need to do is take some chips and rename
these to to my name bidding tokens one
chip equals one diamond so this is two
stacks of diamonds i've got in my hand
so
i believe what we need to do
is we go up to each one we press the
button it opens for five seconds we're
not allowed to go in we're not allowed
to touch anything so we have no idea
what's in there
and
whoa
that's a lot of that's a lot of diamonds
remember these are just diamonds and
then when the bidding closes you have to
exchange these for diamonds oh my
goodness all right let's um open this up
oh
so there's nine diamonds there seven
four there's a good amount of diamonds
in there but there's no way there's more
than 64. oh and what's in here lots of
redstone
jeez
64 diamonds for all of that this is nuts
okay so someone ren has just done
how what could there be something good
in here
there's literally nothing in this one
and people have bet
64 diamonds i don't know if people
realize quite how this works so looking
in here
vincent van gogh entire collection so
there's some paintings in here
okay there's slightly worse bits here
but 32 diamonds for any of this blimey
was it this one this one had all the
diamonds in in a trident
so this is the one that i would bid on
but
there's already 64 diamonds you know
what i'm just gonna put two two diamond
bit in there
i don't win but if if x doesn't um i'll
put four diamonds in no no no no i'll
put 10 in because we know that there's a
block of diamonds there so that's that's
a pretty safe bet that means if x
doesn't actually
trade in his bits for some diamonds
then we will win that lot and
considering that we've got over four
stacks of diamonds that's not a
i did have four stacks of diamonds where
have all my diamonds gone is this some
kind of bug
have my
i'm clicking there there's no
no they're not oh no
let me try relogging
nope
my
my diamonds have definitely gone that is
really weird
i've never seen anything like this
before
my ender chest has everything it had in
nothing else has gone missing
just my diamonds
i'm broke
i actually have no diamonds at all
because something has happened here oh
dear well um i can't bid anything really
cause i haven't got any diamonds i'm
gonna have to
okay so the closing bid happens in like
uh half a week's time so i've got some
time to mine some diamonds i've only bet
and even then x has outbid me
mumbo's gonna make so many diamonds from
this oh boy this isn't good i
wish i didn't cash in all my diamonds
right at the start of the elytra course
i've got nothing now you know i'm just
i'm going to pop these back in here
because
yeah i'm not betting anything that's
kind of put a damper on my day well it
looks like we'll have to get our
diamonds back the hard way we'll have to
go mining again or something but that is
really strange and what i i've
skipped over here but i'm not sure what
this is about seems to be a lot of
things going on here is this the
shopping district like expanded okay so
you can take as much wool as you need
but you have to write what you take is
that it no strings attached you can take
as much wool as you need you just need
to write down what you take oh that's
very very tempting well i'll keep that
in mind but seeing as i have absolutely
no diamonds even if it is free i feel
like there's nothing for free on
hermitcraft so i'm skeptical about that
so i did say at the start of the episode
before i do die two diamonds
someone's tried the elytra course
oh
we're we're making diamonds now
oh man so all of our diamonds are gone
but i did say at the start i was going
to try and beat my score
so that does mark the end of the episode
but if you want to watch me try and beat
my score i'm going to go for a perfect
no hit run
starting now
the key
i've learned and if i hear i'm probably
just going to restart the key is to
constantly spam
rockets to keep your momentum going ah
we're going to start again this no hit
run is going to be difficult it appears
i've only managed to do a no hit run
once and i wasn't recording so it
doesn't count
but hopefully i could beat my old score
and secure my
place in first place
we've got a dangerous part here oh
i'll definitely lost some seconds there
but as long as i don't get hit i think
we'll be fine
through the quidditch hoop
we're going into bamboo canyon now which
has actually had the bamboo removed
since i did my first time so i might be
able to make up some seconds here
through here over the top
under three quadcopt
we've got the concorp run now
left
through this hoop up through tag tower
through this tiny hole
okay we've taken out quite a lot of the
potential damages
but there is a couple more
oh
that's one of the hardest parts of the
route this is gonna be this is a good
run this is a really good run
so we need to go through this hoop hard
right
now this is where oh no
two hits come on every single time those
two hoops get me ah looks like my no hit
run is not today
but that is only two hits only two hits
boom i have no idea what the time was
but it might be better than my usual
so i had a two hit penalty it's always
those two
so i have no idea what my time is going
to be until after i've edited this video
but if it's not any better then well
i'll have to try again later
but anyway that's it for me everyone
thank you very much for watching i hope
you enjoyed this episode and boy oh boy
did we get a lot done today let me know
what you thought about my dragon and let
me know what else we should do in the
build-off
but um
yeah
if any of you see what happens if this
happens to anybody else if anybody's
else's diamonds go missing please do let
me know because i'd really like to know
if there's like a fix for it or if
they've ended up somewhere who knows
either way thank you very much for
watching and good bye